swin.edu.au 2008-06-16

# Privacy

    * Website Feedback

|  |  |   
---  
  
We Value Your Privacy

Swinburne University of Technology acknowledges and respects the privacy of individuals. We advise that much of the information that you may have provided to, or may be asked to provide, to Swinburne University of Technology is 'personal information'. As a general rule, personal information is not released by Swinburne University of Technology to other organisations, except in response to legal requirements such as a subpoena, and information regarding an individual will not be disclosed to a third party without the individual's consent, except where the third party is directly acting as our agent. 

Why Do We Collect Your Information

This information is normally collected for the purposes of processing your application, registration or inquiry for a Swinburne University of Technology course, activity or interest group. Information that we collect will be used for keeping you informed of upcoming events, improving the student experience and assisting us in improving and marketing our services to you. 

How Do We Collect Your Information

Registration

Swinburne University of Technology generally collects information through forms, direct marketing, Internet registration or contracts with external education and training providers. The provision of this personal information is voluntary but if information is not provided, Swinburne University of Technology University may be unable to process your details for the purpose for which they were intended. 

E-Learning

Some Swinburne University of Technology sites may have chat rooms, forums, on-line teaching environments, message boards and or/news groups available to their users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

On-Line Recruitment

We collect personal information from Careerhub.com about Swinburne University students that are registered through the Swinburne University/ Careerhub.com web site. We collect this information to improve student employment and to enhance the student experience. 

Cookies

The Swinburne University of Technology web systems have extensive security features and may temporarily install "cookie(s)" on your computer. These cookie(s) communicates to secure servers at the Swinburne University of Technology to authenticate access to a number of Swinburne University of Technology systems. The cookie(s) do not collect any information about you, or how you are using your computer and only serve to ensure that you have identified yourself with the correct username and password. 

Security

Any personal information that you we collect is held with the strictest confidence. Swinburne University uses and implements industry standards for the security and protection of information collected, and this information is securely stored and access is restricted to authorised personnel only, ensuring that your personal information is protected and safeguarded 

Information Swinburne University collects is used only for the purpose stipulated at the time that the information is collected. Swinburne University is required by law not to reveal, disclose, sell, distribute, rent, licence, share or pass on to any third parties, any personal information that you may have provided to us unless we have your express consent to do so. 

Exceptions to this include:

  * Where there are reasonable grounds to believe that disclosure is necessary to prevent a threat to life or health; and;
  * Where Swinburne University is required to provide information in response to Subpoenas or Warrants or other legal process, including requests from the Australian Stock Exchange.

Access to Your Information

You have a right of access to, and alteration of personal information concerning yourself held by the University, in accordance with Government Legislation. 

Privacy Policy

Swinburne University has a Privacy Policy that can be found on its Policies and Procedures Database, which outlines the ways in which we intends to meet our privacy commitments and details the procedures for making complaints under the Act. The Privacy Policy can be located at: [ http://ppd.swinburne.edu.au/humres/Privacy.htm](http://ppd.swinburne.edu.au/humres/Privacy.htm)

Contact

If staff have any queries in relation to privacy at Swinburne University of Technology, please contact the University Compliance Officer at [trowan@swin.edu.au](mailto:trowan@swin.edu.au) 

|  |   
---
